<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Malay @ WWW</title>
    <link>https://malaybasu.com/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Malay @ WWW</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Malay K Basu. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://malaybasu.com/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CB2-101: Bioinformatics computing</title>
      <link>https://malaybasu.com/teaching/cb2_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malaybasu.com/teaching/cb2_101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CB2-101 is our flagship course. This is a very highly-rated, fast paced, intensive and demanding, workshop-style course designed after NSF immersion learning proposal. The goal is not to make you an expert in bioinformatics, but to make you competent in carrying out bioinformatics research. The emphasis in on skills, not on theoretical expertise. The course is a registered graduate course with full 3 credits, but taught in just 12 working days. The course is designed in such a way so that the participants should be immersed in the material and dedicate full time in the duration of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is offered once a year in November. The course ends one week before Thanksgiving. For details see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmb.path.uab.edu/training/cb2-101.html&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INFO 510: Programming with Biological Data</title>
      <link>https://malaybasu.com/teaching/info_501/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malaybasu.com/teaching/info_501/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course provides students necessary bioinformatics programming and data skills using Linux, MySQL and R. Linux commands and use of scripting languages will be taught in the context of bioinformatics data processing. Basic and practical database skills will be covered. Basic statistics using R to conduct reproducible research will be taught. Students will learn homology search using BLAST, understand basic next-generation sequencing data processing and analysis pipeline development. The focus will be on practical bioinformatics concepts using scripting/programming applied to data analysis problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course run every summer. The dates vary. You can find more information about the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cb2edu/info510&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
